Unbridled. Unbroken. Unbeaten.
Hidalgo is a western, adventure film directed by Joe Johnston.
Set in 1890, this is the story of a Pony Express courier who travels to Arabia to compete with his horse, Hidalgo, in
a dangerous race for a massive contest prize, in an adventure that sends the pair around the world...
Frank Hopkins, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Jazira, played by Zuleikha Robinson.
Sheikh Riyadh, played by Omar Sharif.
Lady Anne Davenport, played by Louise Lombard.
Buffalo Bill Cody, played by J.K. Simmons.
Sakr, played by Adoni Maropis.
Hidalgo is a 2004 epic biographical Western film directed
by Joe Johnston and written by John Fusco.
Based on the legend of the American distance rider Frank Hopkins and his mustang Hidalgo, it recounts
Hopkins' racing his horse in Arabia in 1891 against Bedouins riding pure-blooded Arabian horses.
The film stars Viggo Mortensen, Zuleikha Robinson, and Omar Sharif.
Hidalgo was released by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution under
the Touchstone Pictures label on March 5, 2004.
Upon release, the film received mixed reviews and it underperformed at the box
office, grossing $108.1 million against a budget of $100 million.
The film explores themes of middle east, horse
race, horse, racehorse, biography.